Tom Pollak

A second year Computer Science student studying at the University of York seeking a summer internship in software development or other related fields. I enjoy learning practically on projects and also enjoy researching topics independently. I am most proficient with Python but also have experience in JavaScript and Java. I also have many years of experience with Linux systems and Git version control.

EDUCATION

University of York

September, 2020 - July 2024

MEng Computer Science

York, UK

- Theory 1 (81%), Theory 2 (72%), Theory 3 (78%), Software 1 (95%), Software 2 (94%),
 Systems & Devices 1 (78%), Systems & Devices 2 (71%), Data 1 (72%) Data 2 (72.5%),
 Intelligent Systems 1 (73%) Human Computer Interaction 1 (66%), Human Computer Interaction 2 (70%).
 o Average 77% expected first.
- Member of the university climbing, surf, floorball, poker, chess and ski societies

Lady Manners School

March, 2020

A-Level & GCSEs

Bakewell, UK

- Further Maths (A), Maths (A), Computer Science (A), Physics (A).
- GCSE: 5 8s, 2 7s, 2 6s, 1 5.

TECHNICAL SKILLS & PROJECTS

Each Way Matcher

December 2020 - July 2021

github.com/tom-pollak/each-way-matcher

- Created an automated horse racing betting program as a personal project that makes bets on profitable races.
- Can make arbitrage bets or discover undervalued horses by the bookmaker in each-way type betting.
- Uses an adapted Kelly Criterion equation to calculate the optimal stake and strategy used in a horse race.
- Runs headless on a Raspberry Pi as a scheduled job every day.

York Pirate Game

January 2022 - February 2022

github.com/tom-pollak/pirates

Created an interactive pirate game using Java and LibGDX as part of the ENG1 module.

SANS Institute August, 2020

Windows Forensics Analysis - FOR500 Course

sans.org/cyber-security-courses/windows-forensic-analysis

- Completed the course over a period of two weeks with live lectures and practical sessions.
- Sponsored to take part in the course through the Cyber Discovery programme.

Poker Web Application

April 2019 - July 2020

github.com/tom-pollak/web-poker

- Created a free live poker web app pollakpoker.herokuapp.com.
- Users can create accounts and tables, play poker and chat with other players while competing on a leaderboard.
 - o Uses Python and Django technologies and is deployed using Docker on Heroku.
 - o Uses Django Channels to create web sockets, as to adaptively update the poker game.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Glasshouse Bar September 2021 – Present

Bartender York, UK

Currently working as a bartender at the York University Student Union.

Seafood Bar & Grill July 2021 – September 2021

Waiter

Matlock Bath, UK

Worked as a waiter, waiting tables and serving food.

Derbyshire Police March 2021

Mock Police Witness Interviewee

Ripley, UK

- Role acting as a witness for Derbyshire Police CID Interview Training.
- Involves being interviewed by trainee police detectives, requires proficient communication skills as you must communicate effectively whilst improvising any other details that may not have been available in the brief.

Fishpond June – September 2020

Bartender Matlock Bath, UK

Worked as a bartender, serving drinks and food to customers.

Dukes Barn July 2019

Outdoor Activities Assistant Rowsley, UK

 Working with 10-11 year old children including some groups with special needs on their summer residential camp. I assisted with outdoor activities including canoeing, climbing and low ropes.

Oakenstone Construction

July – September 2019

Labourer Bonsall, UK

SKILLS & INTERESTS

Cyber Discovery

September 2018 – July 2019

- Independently completed the Cyber Discovery Programme run by HM government for teaching students cyber security.
- I was selected as one of the top 500 (of 28,000 students) to attend the Cyber Discovery Elite event in London.

Duke of Edinburgh Award

2018

- Languages Python, Java, Haskell, JavaScript, HTML, SQL, CSS, BASH.
- Technologies Linux, Vim, Git, Django, Pandas, Numpy, LibGDX, Docker, Vue.js, Postgresql, Selenium.
- Interests Mountain biking, Climbing, Poker, Chess, Running, Hockey.

Check out my GitHub github.com/tom-pollak

References available on request